<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Tracy Schulz ]]></title><description><![CDATA[On location professional hair and makeup services for print, video and special events. I specialize in clean work with high sanitation standards. ]]></description><link>https://www.tracydoesmakeup.com/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 02:46:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tracydoesmakeup.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Hot Off The Press!]]></title><description><![CDATA[The November issue of IKON Wedding Magazine has featured one of my brides, and I couldn't be more excited. Molli celebrated her wedding...]]></description><link>https://www.tracydoesmakeup.com/post/hot-off-the-press</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6192e7cfa0740f0022232b8a</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 23:37:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_8e559592f51140518efefbfd0696ba5a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_689,h_895,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tracy Schulz</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The November issue of IKON Wedding Magazine has featured one of my brides, and I couldn't be more excited. Molli celebrated her wedding on a family farm, the fields were golden warm and the skis were blue. I will never forget her first look, as she walked into the opening the wind kicked up and blew her veil on que, she was absolutely stunning. </p>

<p>If any of my brides would like to submit their wedding images for publication I am happy to help.  </p>

<p>These are a few of my favorite pages from this publication. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Work In Time Square NY!]]></title><description><![CDATA[It has always been a dream of mine to one day see my work on a billboard in Time Square NY. I didn't know how to go about making that...]]></description><link>https://www.tracydoesmakeup.com/post/my-work-in-time-square-ny</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6081c909850a25005712672c</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 19:46:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_9014c02915fa41df95d82901a5849df3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_960,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tracy Schulz</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has always been a dream of mine to one day see my work on a billboard in Time Square NY. I didn't know how to go about making that happen, who to speak with or where to start. But like all dreams you work hard and keep trying. In 2018 it finally happened! My first board. I could only image how huge a beautiful it was by the pictures that were sent to me. It was up for 7 months! I never did make it to NY to see it in person but treasure the pictures that were sent to me. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_9014c02915fa41df95d82901a5849df3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_960,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>In September of that year I worked NY Fashion Week and on my last day there with 20 minutes of spare  I ran down 8 blocks to Time Square to see if I could find the location that billboard was,  just so I could see the sized of it. I tell you it was something, the board on that building was huge. As I walked in aw around Time Square looking at all the works of fellow makeup artist it seemed serial that I had joined them with that level of success. As I watched the electronic boards change from one image to the next I was astonished as one of my billboards was still up! Completing that bucket list moment of seeing one in person. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_3ab489f1801c42199ada2e2842bea339~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Since this day I am proud to say I have had 10 billboards in Time Square NY!  1 in Hollywood California, 1 in Las Vegas, 6 in Seattle and 1 in Bend, Oregon. I still find it excited to drive down the street and look up seeing something I helped create.</p>

<p>Here are a few of the billboards. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_bbc9a52a25ac4ed6ba4406eec03bb13b~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_d1d2024fea0f4bbe8cbb5640f120f614~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_7f249fa4b40145e7aeab9d3e7b921d29~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_e988989fcf194a0b8d1385ab8d9fa6fc~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_a5f2ade4b6f44680957fc560de3ac20b~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_01046a3c8f0c4b8a860fdfd5039ba275~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_737cf7e6a7af4b2ab2f9910c29457eb6~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_3b016e81214d4da9baf5b43b8992a7c7~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_4f61e3a69daa4e95beb69389d953192e~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_9a60a148875d417293163a5a3c57edda~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_e593156dd1d94b0ca3c2d14b3b0e4744~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_bf255d3dfe3e4bb481cc8a6e8b3a14df~mv2.jpg"></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bridal Expo! Postponed Due to Covid-19 Restrictions]]></title><description><![CDATA[Brides join me April 1st - April 5th for a Pop-up Workshop on how to choose the right hair and makeup team or stylist for your wedding.]]></description><link>https://www.tracydoesmakeup.com/post/manage-your-blog-from-your-live-site</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7e2123770af600178ac317</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 16:52:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_0a51a8554340450c8edc8d7a44e7e706~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tracy Schulz</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brides join me February 27th at Highland Fields in Forest Grove a 20-acre oasis in the country where you can escape to embrace nature while viewing the event space and wedding vendors to make your dream wedding.  </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_70ad5bc0e2a74369bc999216f865fc15~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_986,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2>Bridal Hair and Makeup Demos!!</h2><p>Not sure what you want for your wedding look or even know what questions to ask, this is the perfect time to see someone in action and get questions answered I will be doing the live demos on our bridal guests. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_78e53c991d974b8694e262ed0cfc3e55~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2>Wedding Vendors!</h2><p>There will be an A list of vendors for you to chat with. Just imaging being able to attend a Bridal Expo without the crowds! You will have the time you need to chat with Wedding Photographers, Wedding Venues, Event Rentals, Videographers, DJ's, Boudoir Photographer, and so many more. </p>

<p>We are limited to the number of brides due to the pandemic restrictions so take advantage of skipping the crowd. Entrance fee is only $35! This won't last long before it is booked up head to <a href="www.chelseydorr.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>www.chelseydorr.com</u></a> for your tickets. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_e22e3649b82f4fcebb032f915c977179~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_245bb94484144489babbc9cf28332e44~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_0a91e4843b354eb1b5f4d31b5d12f6c9~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_0cb041fca8544bfea102fc29198265af~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_bf36eec1a8234957ba7947cda75e0d2b~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_c48c3acfae8c4d8b830788a94a21ef5d~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_f9621bd5cdec467bb2e6b2fd392d3654~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_64eeb2a85b85487fbe53f95d7a468680~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_bea5a20721374a9983e2510e706de836~mv2.jpg"></figure><p>#PortlandBridalShow #BridalExpo #OregonBride #BridalMakeup #BridalHairStyle </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bridal Makeup Trends 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[When it comes to choosing your look every bride wants to be at their best. With the Makeup world blowing up all over social media it is...]]></description><link>https://www.tracydoesmakeup.com/post/design-a-stunning-blog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7e2123770af600178ac316</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 16:52:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_4819bb5c8a414a0b8f4a35a6a9b03261~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_862,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tracy Schulz</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to choosing your look every bride wants to be at their best. With the Makeup world blowing up all over social media it is easy to get swept away in the latest cut crease, graphic liner or a vampy lip. When choosing your makeup look here are a few things to consider. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_7c238c76d8a0466d9d31a26197e76342~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p> </p><h2>Where is the trend going? </h2><p>Well it was clear on the runway this fall that the ever popular over contoured K Kardashian look is on it's way out. How did we ever live before the secrets of contouring made its way to the retail market? The shape shifting things we learned when Instagram and YouTube blew up with tutorials demonstrating how to get the perfect contour with a fork and other utensils. As entertaining as they were professional makeup artist were contouring way before it was a thing. The difference is the subtle way it was applied designed to enhance and not change what you look like. Trends have moved into this direction. The over edited images of flawless skin without pours was not reality. Now a more youthful fresh approach has taken way, where skin looks fresh and glows from within. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_017e935b8439417691a9030da8b95724~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_f9b3eef3ee2643d89a3a91a695362f2a~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_79e4fd2b4d5c44d0867bf92ec3b2e1b9~mv2.jpg"></figure><h2>Rouge </h2><p>A touch of color to the cheek in the way of:  </p><ul>
  <li>Creams that melt into skin for a realistic glow. </li>
  <li>Tones moving from nudes to pinks and coral. </li>
  <li>Soft and natural to just a pop of color. </li>
  <li>The over highlighted skin is toned down to a soft glow. Rudolph should not be making an appearance on your nose this wedding season. </li>
</ul><h2>Sparkle </h2><p>We also saw sparkle on the runway a pop of shimmer in your eyeshadow to brighten the eye will be favored more this year.  Smokey eyes will still be a thing for those who like a more dramatic eye, we will be seeing neutrals, plums and dusty pinks, greens and blue this year. Since a large portion of weddings were postponed in 2020 due to the pandemic we are seeing a blend of last season colors with the new 2021 colors. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_dff2c8982ad04c58867b19744ec8c35a~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_0a51a8554340450c8edc8d7a44e7e706~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_a7d6f72ab984406da6b96b44002993bd~mv2.jpg"></figure><h2>Red</h2><p>Red lips made a comeback in a strong way. A soft neutral eye with a rich romantic red lip and a pop of gloss is a timeless classic look. If red is to strong for you try a nude with a pop of berry tone, or even a shear berry stained lip will do the trick. </p>
<h2>Most Importantly</h2><p>You want to feel like you when you look in the mirror. If you wouldn't feel like yourself with you liner having a little flick at the end be sure to tell your makeup artist. I always tell my clients my goal is for you to look like you, just a more famous version of you. Radiant skin with that glow that comes from within. Lashes will still make an appearance in bridal. Just remember they are there to enhance your eyes not weight them down and make your eyes look heavy or tired.  Use the makeup to bring out the best in you so you are the star on your big day. You'll want people to remember how radiant you looked not how memorable your makeup look was. </p>
<h2>One last thing</h2><p> When you look back on your photos you will want them to look timeless, like the moment just happened yesterday. I often hear from Mother of the Bride how date stamped their photos looked with trends from that era. Many wishing they had gone more traditional. </p>

<p>#Makeuptrends #Bridalmakeup #2021weddingtrends #2021BridalMakeup </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is it safe for me to get my makeup done? ]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are all concerned for the health and safety of our loved ones and ourselves. The impact of Covid-19 really shook the world and we...]]></description><link>https://www.tracydoesmakeup.com/post/grow-your-blog-community</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7e2123770af600178ac315</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 15:52:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_f22265f4afff491e9b0e8fa839345b1c~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tracy Schulz</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are all concerned for the health and safety of our loved ones and ourselves. The impact of Covid-19 really shook the world and we started realizing what was taken for granted and how to adjust to the new norm. In this article I will break down what I have learned over the years of extensive schooling, the classes I took during the pandemic to prepare to return to work, and the changes made to work mitigating risks for both you and I. In a nutshell Yes it is safe for you to have your makeup done with a professional who mitigates risks and puts safety and sanitation first following all Health Department Guidelines.  </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/4b45c2be322e43929a038a2851cc029d.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What can I do to ensure I am choosing the right Makeup Artist? </strong></p>
<p>When hiring a Makeup Artist do your home work. Ask if they are State Licensed, someone who holds a state license has successfully completed beauty school and past their state boards governed by the Health Department. Certified Makeup Artist is not the same as Licensed.  You can check and see if the artist you want to hire has a license by going to the Oregon Health Authority website or by clicking this link. <a href="https://elite.hlo.state.or.us/OHLOPublicR/LPRBrowser.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://elite.hlo.state.or.us/OHLOPublicR/LPRBrowser.aspx</u></a> </p>
<h2>What's the difference between Licensed and Certified? </h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_95c62deae9154e9aaa453f2bcb899854~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>When you become licensed you have proven to the Health Department you are competent not only in the areas of study but also in Safety and Sanitation. There is a required amount of hours you must be in school including practical time working on clients. You have laws to follow that ensure the safety of your clients and your licensed allows you to do services Certified Artist can not do. A Freelance Authorization allows your to preform service outside of a salon, like at a wedding, special event or in someone's home. These licenses need to be renewed to remain active and the Freelance Authorization requires an exam to remain current. </p>

<p>To become a Certified Makeup Artist you can take an online 30 minimum class where you never have to apply makeup to anyone. The sanitation is not overseen by a Health Department and the sanitation portion my not apply in your state or be accurate.  I have talked to may artist who were miss informed from these classes. Certified programs are more economical than Beauty School which is why they are so popular they are fast and affordable. Some of the Certified Makeup Schools offer hands on and go into more depth with they different types of makeup such as special effects to event makeup application techniques than Beauty Schools do. Those who specialize in Makeup (licensed or certified) usually take classes annually to continue their education which is a good question to ask as well. </p>

<p>Ask yourself if you would be confident and comfortable going into a salon for a color service knowing the stylist was never formally trained? What about a spa treatment? Would you go into a spa for a facial or light therapy and feel comfortable knowing the Esthetician never attended school and got her license? If you think about it Makeup artist are working very close to you, their hands, tools and product can come into contact with your skin, eyes and mouth. If these tools are not properly cleaned and maintained you are at risk for infection!   </p>

<p><strong>What Questions Should I Ask?</strong></p><ol>
  <li>Where did you go to school? </li>
  <li>Are you a licensed Esthetician? </li>
  <li>How long have you been working? </li>
  <li>Do you have a website? Instagram is a great tool but a professional will have a website.</li>
  <li>How do you maintain your brushes? (see my blog post on cleaning brushes)</li>
  <li>How to you clean your product? (see my blog post on my pandemic kit)</li>
  <li>What are your guidelines while working in the pandemic? https://sharedsystems.dhsoha.state.or.us/DHSForms/Served/le2342F.pdf</li>
  <li>What can I expect when you arrive? </li>
  <li>Is there anything you will need access to? </li>
</ol><p>If you like their work but still are not sure ask for a trial, this is a great way to see first hand how they work. If you like the work jive with their personality then hire them. Think of this as an investment into your health and safety. </p>

<p>These are samples of Certifications I received during the pandemic as I continued to do research. None of them were as good as the education I received in Beauty School.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_3a93b933a17a47d98680231ab7ee82ba~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_3408d0cac89148c594b3178fb7933c90~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/86af31_948e3d68756742ee80a4db0659ce3e8e~mv2.jpg"></figure><p>Oregon Licenses  COS•CL•10189413,  COS•FT•435326,  COS•HA•435326 Did you know someone who holds a licenses must display it while working? </p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>